Hi, my name is Niklas Noldin.

I'm a *designer* and *creative coder* from the Austrian alps. I live in *Barcelona*, *Spain* and I'm available to work. Following my education in both *design and IT*, I spent many years developing *web apps on a global scale*. Now, I aim to apply my know-how in both fields creatively.

Experience

Sam Digital Head of Development

I co-founded <u>sam-digital.com</u> which helps companies in the metal industry to manage their liquid household.

January 2021 - present

Remote

Return on Art Chief Technology Officer

March 2023 - September 2023

Educational leave

March 2022 - February 2023

Frontend Engineer

October 2020 - February 2022

Vienna, Austria

Taronja Escuela de Español Fullstack Engineer Mobile and Event Coordinator

August - December 2019

Valencia, Spain

Atelier Christian Mariacher Graphic Design Internship

July – August 2016 and July – August 2015

Innsbruck, Austria

Circus – Büro für Gestaltung Graphic Design Internship

July - August 2014

Innsbruck, Austria

Skills

Creative

TouchDesigner, Resolume Arena, Cinema 4D, Cavalry, Figma, Final Cut Pro, Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Technologic

JavaScript, CSS, Web Animation, Vue.js, Processing/p5.js, d3.js, PHP, Laravel, SQL

Soft Skills

Problem Solving, Product Development, Entrepreneurial Thinking

Education

HTL Construction and Design Specialized High School Degree in Graphic Design

September 2012 – June 2017

Innsbruck, Austria

University of Applied Science Salzburg

BSc. in Multimedia Technology with a Major in Web Development

October 2017 - September 2020

Salzburg, Austria

University of Applied Arts Vienna

Educational Leave

Arts & Science, Stage Design, Exhibition Project Management September 2022 – February 2023

Vienna, Austria

University of Technology Vienna

Educational Leave

Data Visualization, User Experience Design

February - July 2022

Vienna, Austria

Volunteer Work

Junge Talstation Event Venue

Member of the organization who runs an event venue inside an abandoned cable car station.

Design, Event Marketing, Social Media, Renovation, Bar Keeping, Projectionist Innsbruck, Austria

Languages

German Native (C2)
English Advanced (C1)
Spanish Elementary (A2)
Catalan Beginner (A1)



hello@niklasnold.in +43 66414 59 315 www.niklasnold.in Carrer de Coll i Vehí 131 401a 08026, Barcelona, Spain Date of Birth: 16.10.1997 Nationality: Austrian, Italian NIE: Z-0895256-D

Class B Driver's License

Social

linkedin.com/in/niklasnoldin instagram.com/nippiofficial